Andy Brown iOS Developer

andybrown41@icloud.com · github.com/ab492 · 07591 454 148 · Putney, London

Profile

I am a self-trained iOS developer looking for an opportunity to move into a full-time developer role. My previous work experience includes working as a Visual Effects Data Coordinator in film and television, but over the last two years I have been using my spare time to study iOS development. I am a proactive, detail-orientated employee looking to bring my skills to a team environment.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF EXETER, 2010-2013 First Class BSc. Honors Degree in Mathematics BIRCHWOOD HIGH SCHOOL, BISHOP'S STORTFORD, 2003-2010 3 A-Levels (A*-A), 10 GCSEs (A*-C)

Portfolio

The two apps on my GitHub profile, Skrilla and FlipFlopWeather, demonstrate a number of key developer skills:

- Self-motivation: Developing these apps in my spare time involved persistence as I dealt with and learned from various problems, reading around issues I came across and asking for guidance on StackOverflow.
- Organisation: My projects are presented in as clear a way as possible with organised project files, comments on more complex methods and clear documentation on GitHub to ensure clarity for an outside reader.
- Technical skills: Design patterns such as MVC, MVVM and coordinators; data persistence; parsing JSON from an external API; writing clear data models; using 3rd party libraries; source control with Git. Each GitHub page lists more specific technologies used.

Employment History

'ALADDIN' - DISNEY - VISUAL EFFECTS DATA COORDINATOR, **APRIL 2017-APRIL 2019**

Reference: Victoria Keeling (Visual Effects Producer)

My role was to manage all of the data generated throughout the two years of production. Responsibilities included:

- Tracking and distributing Director's notes on the thousands of shots and versions, requiring acute attention-to-detail in a high pressured environment to ensure nothing was missed.
- Point of call for technical issues within the department, requiring me to work independently and take initiative to prioritise solving problems as they arose while maintaining a cheerful attitude.

Employment History (Continued)

• The planning and implementation of a 4K screening room with a high speed connection to the US Disney team. This involved liaising with multiple International teams, requiring patience and proactivity to meet expectations within a very tight timeframe.

'LIFE' - SKYDANCE FILMS - VISUAL EFFECTS ASSISTANT, OCTOBER 2016-MARCH 2017

'LIFE' - SKYDANCE FILMS - PRODUCTION ASSISTANT, MARCH 2016-OCTOBER 2016

'FLOWERS SERIES ONE' - KUDOS PRODUCTIONS - PRODUCTION RUNNER, SEPTEMBER 2015-JANUARY 2016

PRINCESS PRODUCTIONS - OFFICE RUNNER AND PRODUCTION RUNNER, JANUARY 2015-SEPTEMBER 2015

Other Interests

In my spare time I love to cook and travel; I recently spent a month travelling around Italy perfecting my pasta making. I'm also a keen runner, having completed two marathons and keen to run another.